VIBHUTI KAVDE

+91-7224840396, Pune, India

vibhutikavde27@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

A dedicated counselling psychologists with experience in providing with a safe space to open up. I have worked with children and young adults. I am trained I taking psychological assessments, counselling and maintain record through case history keeping. I have also been part of volunteer programs which have strengthened my understanding of mental health and their treatment.

EDUCATION

Masters in Counselling Psychology- SNDT Women's University, Pune

Bachelor of Arts (Hons.) in Applied Psychology – Amity University, Madhya Pradesh

EXPERIENCE

EMOTIONAL FIRST-AID RESPONDER (EFAIR), June 2021- Present

Praan Mental Wellness, Remote

- I have been an EFAIR for the past three years
- In my three years of journey, I have been through various training sessions and explored several topics like overthinking parenting styles and trauma care
- Praan has trained me in identifying individuals going through distress supporting them, providing a nonjudgemental space to express lastly guiding them to seek the right professional if needed.

DISTRESS HELPINE VOLUNTEER, October 2023- March 2024

Praan Mental Wellness, Remote

- Delivering safe space and assistance to suicidal as well as distressed clients
- Managed cases of transgender identity issues, examination anxiety, major depressive disorder.
- Took training from the organization for supporting individuals undergoing distress and how to manage clients with suicidal tendencies.
- Managing record of the cases through case studies

INTERN PSYCHOLOGIST, September 2023- March 2024

Kshitij Foundation, Pune

- Worked with children between the ages 12-13
- Administration of psychological tests
- Data feeding and analysis
- Session planning and conducting sessions
- Counselling

TRAINEE PSYCHOLOGIST, July 2023

ThePsykeyLife, Remote

- Supervision in therapy training help understanding possible challenges that can come during sessions
- Through role play sessions and timely guidance from the mentors enable me to face the clients

INTERN, June 2021-July 2021

Akshar Training & Consultancy, Remote

- Learnt techniques like forgiveness therapy, relaxation techniques likes JPMR
- Leant to take case history and Mental Status Examination

SKILLS

- Psychological assessments
- Empathy
- Nonjudgemental approach
- Record keeping
- Spontaneous
- Good communication
- Curriculum development